# Curriculum Vitae

Ronald Pieterse Burgemeester van Lennepweg 48 2101 RH Heemstede

mobile: +31 (0)6 41373596

email: ronald@ahrendee.com

web: <u>ahrendee.com</u>

date of birth: 19 december 1970

nationality: Dutch

# Profile

Fast-learning, autodidact, professional, drives for result.

Passionate for new technologies. Problem solver with good interpersonal skills. Always looking for new challenges and new technologies to learn.

Real team-player, working in scrum teams for many years.

The last few years my interest has shifted to JavaScript technologies and I working mainly with Angular for web-development and NestJS / NodeJS in the back-end, building microservices.

# Working experience

### July 2021 - present : Senior Angular developer at Rabobank Utrecht

Working on cards applications in Payments area in the mono-repo of the platform Senses 2.

Technologies: Angular 15, RxJS, NgRx, NX Workspaces, Azure DevOps

# June 2021 - July 2021 : Angular developer at De Volksbank

Project: Betalen / Overboeken (Payments & Transfers)

Technologies: Angular 10, RxJS, Cucumber, Gherkin, OpenAPI.

### March 2021 - May -2021: Angular developer at Wunderman Thompson Commerce

Project: SNAP/SNEX (Agent / CustomerService web application for SharkNinja)

Technologies: Angular 10, NgRX, RxJS, Jest, Ts-Mockito, Swagger-UI.

### March 2020 - present : Full-stack developer for augustlife.nl / ahrendee.com

*Project*: Building the full stack for the website of rock band August Life (http://augustlife.nl) and my own company web site on ahrendee.com

Front-end: Angular 9 / 10, Material Design, RxJS, NgRx, TypeScript, HTML5, SCSS, deployed on Github Pages. Including custom built webshop with Paypal and IDeal payment functionality. End-to-end testing is done with Cypress Framework. Wiremock is used for api mocking.

Back-end: NodeJS, Express, Rest API with JWT (JSON Web Tokens), Deployed on Heroku

Database: Cloud MongoDB (Atlas)

Juli 2020 - Februari 2021 : Full-stack developer at TNO GD&IT

Project: BRO application (former DINO application)

Technologies: Angular 10, Karma, Jasmin, Java 8 / 11, Webservices (REST / SOAP), Swagger-UI, Docker, ReadyAPI, Quarkus, OpenShift, RestEasy, MapStruct, RestAssured, Mockito.

# September 2017 - March 2020 : Lead front-end developer at Rabobank

Setting up and working on cards (debit-/credit) applications in Payments area in the monorepo of the platform Senses 2. Also mentoring newer front-end developers from India and the Netherlands.

*Project*: Apple Pay responsive front-end - Front-end development using AngularJS, Angular 8, RxJS, NGRX and Ionic. Test framework CodeceptJS and Karma with Wiremock API mock system.

Project: Productservices Cards - Front-end development using AngularJS, Angular 8 and Ionic.

*Technologies*: Technologies I worked with include Angular 8+, Ionic, AngularJS, NodeJS, NPM, Yarn, SCSS, Gulp, Grunt, Java, Spring Boot, Azure, PCF, Docker, Jenkins, Sonar, Swagger.

#### June 2017 - August 2017: Front-end developer at Prospery

Project: Prospery – Short running project for a Marketing website

Technologies: Technologies include NodeJS, NPM, Less, Sass, Gulp, HTML, Javascript, CSS.

#### March 2017 - May 2017 : Software Engineer at Kadaster

Project: KOERS - Frontend development

*Technologies*: Technologies include Angular (v1.5), Typescript, ES6, Webpack, NodeJS, HTML, Javascript, CSS.

Other technologies and Frameworks include Maven, Git, GitHub, JIRA, IntelliJ, Karma, Protractor.

#### October 2016 - February 2017 : Software Engineer at ING

Project: Savings (Open&Close) / Digital 2.0

*Technologies*: Technologies include Polymer, AngularJS, NodeJS, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Java and Spring-REST and Spring-WS.

Other technologies and Frameworks include Maven, Git, Junit, Mockito, IntelliJ, Gulp, Grunt, Jasmine, Karma, Sinon, Protractor.

#### July 2015 - September 2016 : Software Engineer at Rabobank

*Project*: SABA – requesting and discontinuing accounts, creditcards, etc for businesses online and local Rabobank branches.

Technologies: Technologies include AngularJS, NodeJS, HTML, Javascript, CSS, Freemarker, Velocity as well as Java, Spring Webservices, Spring REST, Hibernate, JPA and Spring Security.

Other technologies and Frameworks include Maven, Git, SVN, Jenkins, Sonar, Junit, Mockito, IntelliJ, Gulp, Grunt, Jasmine, Karma, Protractor, XML, JSON.

### February 2015 - June 2015: Software Engineer at DTG

Project: detelefoongids.nl

Technologies: Java, Freemarker, together with GWT, HTML, javascript and CSS. On the backend mainly Java; SEO data aggregation is done using Solr, the search engine/indexing platform. Aggregated data is stored in MongoDB.

Other technologies include Maven, SVN, Jenkins.

# August 2014 - January 2015 : Software Engineer at UWV

Project: Digitalization dismissal process.

*Technologies*: Frontend technologies include NodeJS, AngularJS, Brunch and Bower, together with HTML and CSS. At the front- and backend the latest versions of Spring MVC, Spring Web-Flow, REST webservices and Oracle DB. Other technologies include Maven, SVN, Git, Jenkins.

## September 2013 – June 2014 : Software Engineer at KLM (Royal Dutch Airlines)

Project: EBT / Search.

I worked in the EBT-AM scrum team, the maintenance team for the *Electronic Booking Tool* web application and secondly in the Search web application team (<a href="www.klm.com/home/nl/nl">www.klm.com/home/nl/nl</a>). Both teams worked according to the TDD principle.

Technologies: On the backend the latest versions of Spring MVC, Hibernate, Groovy, SOAP and REST webservices and so on. On the frontend HTML, CSS, Grunt, Sass, JSP, JSTL, BackboneJS and of course with jQuery to name but a few. Further technologies and frameworks include Windows 7, Netbeans, IntelliJ, Eclipse, Maven, Ant, Git, Git bash, Tomcat and Oracle DB.

### July 2011 - July 2013 : Software Developer at Oracle Health Insurance

Project: OHI Self Service webapplication.

Technologies: On the frontend Java with Struts and Tiles, on the backend Spring (including Spring webservices) and Hibernate. I also worked extensively on improvement of test coverage and code compliance of the application using JUnit, Jenkins and Sonar.

## January 2006 - July 2011: Java Developer & SOA Architect at Tripolis Solutions

*Project*: Tripolis Dialogue e-marketing webapplication. All SOA architecture aspects and social media connectivity.

Technologies: On the backend the latest versions of Java and Spring incl. Spring Webflow, Spring MVC, Spring JDBC, Spring AOP and Spring Social. Webservice frameworks include CXF and Axis (v1.4 and 2). On the frontend Spring MVC, JSP and Sitemesh.

Project: Tripolis SystemWeb. Technologies: Grails / Groovy and Wicket.

#### May 2005 - January 2006 : Java Developer at Veritate

Project: Veritate Mail (existing webapplication).

Technologies: Java, Struts and Hibernate.

# January 2001 - April 2005 : Java Developer at Eperium Business Solutions

*Project*: Intershop / Enfinity client implementations. Multiple e-commerce implementations for ECI and the Auping Match store application for Auping.

Technologies: Perl with Intershop 4, Java with Enfinity and Suite 6.

# May 1994 - December 2000 : Prison guard at the Over-Amstel penal institution

prison guard long- and short-term sentenced men.

### Before May 1994

Various jobs, a.o. entertainer on the island of Menorca, lock keeper at the Duivendrechtse Bridge and Groote Zeesluis in Muiden, warehouse keeper.

# Education

I have done and continue to do a lot of self study concerning Java technology and various Java frameworks incl. the various modules of Spring, Hibernate, CXF as well as integration possibilities with social media networks.

In 2011 I followed a 3 day PL-SQL course at Oracle University.

In 2010 I attended a Certified SOA Architect course at SOA School, from Thomas Erl. This course was held in Hamburg and executed by SOAPark. I completed 2 exams for the modules presented there giving me the title 'SOA Professional'.

I attended the first Grails Exchange seminar in London, in 2007. This was hosted by the lead developers of both Grails and Groovy.

I attended several seminars with Rod Johnson (creator of Spring Framework) in the U.K. and the Netherlands (2006 - 2007).

Throughout the years I attended several Java seminars like Devoxx/Javapolis (Belgium) and J-Fall and J-Spring (Netherlands).

Intershop Suite 6 at Eperium(4 day course, 2004).

Java Programming Language and Object Oriented Programming at Sun, Amersfoort (4 day course, 2003).

Prison guard at the Over-Amstel penal institution (8 weeks, 1994).

Course for Application Programmer in COBOL (1988).

Mavo (1983 - 1987).

# Interests and hobbies

Outside of my work I enjoy making music; I play bass guitar in my rock band August Life, piano and keyboards. I also like riding my motorcycle, currently a Triumph Tiger XCa from 2018.

# Languages

Dutch (mother tongue), English (fluent), German (sufficient)

# **Technologies**

#### Programming and development in general

**Languages / Frameworks**: Front-end: Angular (Typescript / Javascript). Back-end: NestJS (Typescript), NodeJS (Javascript), Java and Groovy. XML, XSD, JSON and WSDL as used in SOAP and REST webservices.

I have also programmed in Python, Perl and PHP but have less experience in those languages.

**Web- and Application-servers**: NGINX, Express, Apache HTTPServer, Tomcat, Resin, Glassfish, Jboss, Websphere and Weblogic.

Service frameworks: CXF, Spring-WS, Axis 1 and 2.

Search frameworks: Lucene, Solr

**Test frameworks / Tools**: TestNG, JUnit, JMeter, EasyMock, PowerMock, Mockito, Selenium, Fitnesse. On the front-end Jest, WebDriverIO, CodeceptJS, Protractor, Cucumber, Karma, Sinon. Postman.

IDE's: IntelliJ-IDEA, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, WebStorm, Netbeans, Android Studio, Aptana Studio

**CI/CD**: Azure DevOps, GitHub Pages, BitBucket, GitHub, Ant, Maven 1 and 2, Continuum, Luntbuild, Hudson, Jenkins, Sonar, PCF.

Databases: MySQL, IBM DB2, Oracle XE / 8i / 10g / 11g and MongoDB.

**Object Relational Mapping (ORM) Frameworks**: JPA - Hibernate, EclipseLink. **NoSQL:** Mongoose for MongoDB (NoSQL; not an ORM framework).

**Web**: HTML, Angular JS, Angular 15, TypeScript, Polymer, CSS, JSP, Sitemesh, Tiles, Spring Framework (incl. Spring Boot, Spring Webflow, Spring MVC, Spring JDBC, Spring AOP, Spring Social etc), Apache Wicket, Jakarta Struts, Freemarker and Velocity.

e-commerce frameworks: Intershop 4, Intershop Enfinity and Intershop Suite 6.

Version control: Git, SVN, CVS.